Center for Community Studies Records
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Activities and Programs, 1825-1976; nam_ua652.004-2; 12 cubic ft.
  - Sovereignty, Situations, and Security, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_373 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Special Education, 1967; nam_ua652.004-2_374 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Special Projects, 1964-1965; nam_ua652.004-2_375 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Speech Therapy Clinic, Photographs, 1955; nam_ua652.004-2_376 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Standing, T.G., 1965-1966; nam_ua652.004-2_377 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Standing, T.G. ,The Problems of Consensus in the Modern Community, 1962; nam_ua652.004-2_378 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - State Carities Aid Associations, 1964; nam_ua652.004-2_379 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - State University College for Teachers at Buffalo, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_380 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - State University, Rensselaerville Institute Programs, 1961; nam_ua652.004-2_381 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - A Statistical Study of the Wallingford School System, 1946 September; nam_ua652.004-2_382 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Structural and Functional Change for Cooperation as an Aspect of Complex Organization Adaptation, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_383 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Student and Academic Conference, 1976; nam_ua652.004-2_384 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Student Community Job Assignments, 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_385 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Student Details, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_386 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Student Details, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_387 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Student Interviews, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_388 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Student Opinion Panel, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_389 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Student Opinion Panel, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_390 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Student Participation in College and Community Activities, 1950; nam_ua652.004-2_391 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1947; nam_ua652.004-2_392 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1947; nam_ua652.004-2_393 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_394 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_395 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_396 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_397 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_398 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_399 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_400 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_401 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_402 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_403 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_404 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_405 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_406 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_407 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_408 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_409 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_410 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_411 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_412 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_413 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Student Questionnaires, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_414 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - "A Study of the Community Aspirations of Amsterdam, New York", 1964; nam_ua652.004-2_415 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Study of Opinion on Medicine and Child Health, 1956-1957; nam_ua652.004-2_416 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Study of Opinion on Medicine and Child Health, 1956-1957; nam_ua652.004-2_417 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Study of Opinion on Medicine and Child Health, 1956-1957; nam_ua652.004-2_418 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Supplementary Information on Assistantships and Fellowships, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_419 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Surveys, Students, 1954-1961; nam_ua652.004-2_420 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Swimming Surveys, 1962; nam_ua652.004-2_421 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Swire, Leslie, Educational Philosophy, 1976; nam_ua652.004-2_422 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Syracuse University Students Development Test, 1946; nam_ua652.004-2_423 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Teacher In-service Education Inventory, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_424 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Teaching Internship, 1964; nam_ua652.004-2_425 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Temporary Shelter and Detention Care of Children in Albany and Rensselaer Counties, 1953-1954; nam_ua652.004-2_426 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Term Papers, Students, 1952-1953; nam_ua652.004-2_427 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Testing Materials, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_428 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Third Annual Curriculum Conference for School Administrators: The Disaffected Child, 1964; nam_ua652.004-2_429 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Student, 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_430 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Trends in High School Subjects, 1948-1949; nam_ua652.004-2_431 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Twenty-Second Annual Meeting of the Society for Applied Anthropology, 1963; nam_ua652.004-2_432 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Student, 1976; nam_ua652.004-2_433 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - The University Certificate, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_434 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - University Community Cooperation Project, 1949-1953; nam_ua652.004-2_435 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - University Community Cooperation Project, 1950-1955; nam_ua652.004-2_436 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - University Community Cooperation Project, 1950-1955; nam_ua652.004-2_437 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - The University of the State of New York, Education Department, 1962; nam_ua652.004-2_438 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1951-1973; nam_ua652.004-2_439 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1954-1975; nam_ua652.004-2_440 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1960-1962; nam_ua652.004-2_441 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1962-1965; nam_ua652.004-2_442 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Van Cleve, Donald, 1965-1970; nam_ua652.004-2_443 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Van Corlaer School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_444 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Vaughn, Harold A. Jr., 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_445 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Vassar Summer Institute "What Can Communities Do?", 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_446 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Student, Educational Philosophy 601, 1976; nam_ua652.004-2_447 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - What is the Nature of the Problem Facing our Communities, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_448 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Wick, Rollo E., Correspondence, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_449 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Student, Dissertation Proposal, 1964; nam_ua652.004-2_450 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Woodlawn School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_451 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Woodlawn School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_452 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Workshop Plans, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_453 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Workshops, 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_454 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Workshops, 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_455 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Wynne, John P., Philosophies of Educations, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_456 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Yates School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_457 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Yates School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_458 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Student, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_459 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Zoller School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_460 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Zoller School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_461 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Courses, 1951-1953; nam_ua652.004-2_462 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Census Classification Project, 1825-1890; nam_ua652.004-2_463 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Students, The Community Centered School, 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_464 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Geneseo-Cortland Conference, 1951-1952; nam_ua652.004-2_465 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - High School Student Logs, 1937-1939; nam_ua652.004-2_466 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Illich, Ivan, Why We Must Abolish Schooling, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_467 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - The Immigrant and the Public School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_468 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The Immigrant and the Public School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_469 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - The Immigrant and the Public School, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_470 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - New York College for Teachers Student Participation Study, 1954; nam_ua652.004-2_471 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Projective Devices, 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_472 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Public Opinion Polls, 1953; nam_ua652.004-2_473 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Research, 1951; nam_ua652.004-2_474 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1935-1938; nam_ua652.004-2_475 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1937; nam_ua652.004-2_476 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1937; nam_ua652.004-2_477 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1938; nam_ua652.004-2_478 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1938; nam_ua652.004-2_479 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1939; nam_ua652.004-2_480 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1939; nam_ua652.004-2_481 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1939; nam_ua652.004-2_482 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1940; nam_ua652.004-2_483 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Student Questionnaires, 1952 March 20; nam_ua652.004-2_484 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Survey of High School Student Activities, 1952; nam_ua652.004-2_485 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Surveys on Social Agencies, Undated; nam_ua652.004-2_486 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Publications, 1946-1968; nam_ua652.004-3; 1.2 cubic ft.
  This series includes newsletters, reports, and studies published both by the Center for Community Studies and other organizations. Newsletters include the Center for Community Studies' Education Newsletter and the State University College of Albany's Faculty Bulletin of Information (F.B.I.). This series also includes articles, surveys and publications on prisons (such as Sing Sing), and segregation.
  - The ABCs of Local School Districts in New York State, 1960; nam_ua652.004-3_1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Academically Talented: Problems and Programs, 1961; nam_ua652.004-3_2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alpenfels, Ethel J., Sense & Nonsense About Race, New York, 1946; nam_ua652.004-3_3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Alpenfels, Ethel and W.M. Krogman, Race Against Time: An Introductory Anthropology for Young, Undated; nam_ua652.004-3_4 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - American Unity: To Secure These Rights, 1947; nam_ua652.004-3_5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Americas Tenth Man, Southern Regional Council, 1947; nam_ua652.004-3_6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Amsterdam Survey, Undated; nam_ua652.004-3_7 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bienstok, Theodore, and William C. Sayres, Problems of Secondary Education in International Perspectives, 1959-02; nam_ua652.004-3_8 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Center for Community Studies, Newsletter, 1952; nam_ua652.004-3_9 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Charting Intercultural Education, 1954-1955; nam_ua652.004-3_10 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cole, Stewart G., and Helen G. Troger, How Can Majority and Minority Groups Contribute to Democracy? Democratic Discussions No. 10, 1943-1944; nam_ua652.004-3_11 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - College-Community Relationships in New York State, 1953; nam_ua652.004-3_12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Community, 1958; nam_ua652.004-3_13 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Coolidge,Calvin, Address by the President (1925), Jewish Contributions to American Democracy, 1940; nam_ua652.004-3_14 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Education Newsletter, 1951-1953; nam_ua652.004-3_15 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Bulletin of Information, 1952; nam_ua652.004-3_16 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fielder, Miriam Foster, A Study of the Socio-Economic Status of a Group of Public School Children with Hearing Defects, Child Development 22.3, 1951 September; nam_ua652.004-3_17 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Fielder, Miriam Foster, Teachers Problems with Hard of Hearing Children, Journal of Educational Research, 1949 April; nam_ua652.004-3_18 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fellowship House, Extinguish Hatred, Philadelphia, Undated; nam_ua652.004-3_19 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Formation of Educational Policies: A Comparative Analysis, 1968; nam_ua652.004-3_20 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Grier, Eunice, and George, Race Relations in the Albany-Troy Area: A Profile for 1957, 1957 November; nam_ua652.004-3_21 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Halsey, Margaret, Some of My Best Friends are Soldiers, New York, 1944; nam_ua652.004-3_22 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Hightower, Estelle, Race Relations in the South, New York, 1942; nam_ua652.004-3_23 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Horner, Harlan H., Education in New York State, 1784-1954, nam_ua652.004-3_24 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Improving InterGroup Relations in School and Community Life, 1946; nam_ua652.004-3_25 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Intercultural Education through the Social Studies, 1945; nam_ua652.004-3_26 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Johnson, Eric A., Intolerance, New York City, 1947; nam_ua652.004-3_27 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - The July 1953 Prophylaxis Program for Poliomyelitis in Chemung Audsteuben Counties, 1954; nam_ua652.004-3_28 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - McEntire, Davis, and Robert B. Powers, A Guide to Race Relations For Police Officers, Police Training Bulletin, Department of Justice, State of California, 1947; nam_ua652.004-3_29 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Members of the Staff of Junior High School 47, A New Approach To The Education of Two and Three Year Old Deaf Children, Volta Review, 1949 May-June; nam_ua652.004-3_30 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Nelson, Robert L., The Negro in Athletics, New York, 1940; nam_ua652.004-3_31 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Nelson, Rose K., and Dorothy L. Cole, The Negros Contribution to Music in America, New York, 1941; nam_ua652.004-3_32 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Newsletter from the State University of New York, 1952; nam_ua652.004-3_33 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Preparing the Offender in the Institutions of the New York State Department of Corrections, 1954; nam_ua652.004-3_34 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - The Problem of Violence, Undated; nam_ua652.004-3_35 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Sing Sing Prison, 1953; nam_ua652.004-3_36 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - State Education Department, 1952; nam_ua652.004-3_37 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - A Survey of the Humanagement of a Public School System, 1949; nam_ua652.004-3_38 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Survey Graphic: Segregation, 1947; nam_ua652.004-3_39 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Vickery, William E., and Morris Edward Opler, A Redefinition of Prejudice for Purposes of Social Science Research, Human Relations 1.4, 1948; nam_ua652.004-3_40 (Box 3, Folder 40)